Stephen Johnston

■ sdjohnston1990@gmail.com stephendjohnston.github.io in linkedin.com/in/stephendjohnston

PROFILE

I am a full-stack software developer with a passion for collaborating to solve challenging problems and an enthusiasm for continuous learning and improvement. I have multiple years of experience in the JavaScript and Ruby ecosystems, as well as experience with various frameworks and AWS.

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer, Co-Creator, *Herald* □

2023 – present

Herald is an open source application that simplifies deployment of a full observability solution for logs, traces and metrics.

- Engineered the automatic provisioning and deployment of an observability pipeline, condensing a complex multi-application deployment (Elasticsearch, Logstash, Kibana, Fleet Server) into just a few simple steps.
- Designed and implemented a distributed architecture using AWS Cloud Development Kit (CDK).
- Abstracted application components and services into custom CDK constructs for deployment on AWS resources.
- Reduced pipeline congestion and potential data loss by architecting a multi-cluster, autoscaling Elasticsearch service with automated node discovery.
- Implemented infrastructure for automated certificate generation for enabling TLS encryption across all application services.
- Containerized applications and solved complex configuration issues by building custom Docker images.
- Created a CLI to facilitate set-up, configuration, deployment, and tear-down of the Herald application.
- Authored comprehensive case study discussing the use case, design decisions, and implementation challenges of building Herald 🛮
- Collaborated with a remote team of 4 developers across 3 time zones using an agile workflow

Software Developer, *Self-employed*

2019 - 2023

- PanicBin tool for inspecting and debugging webhooks (Node.js, Express, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, React)
- BuyPal e-commerce shopping-cart app (Node.js, Express, MongoDB, React)
- Taskify productivity app for tracking and managing habits and tasks (Node.js, Express, JavaScript, Handlebars)

SKILLS

Languages & Frameworks

JavaScript, Ruby, Go, SQL, React, Express, Sinatra, Handlebars, *jQuery, Jest, HTML/CSS*

Other Technologies

Node.js, Git/Github, Docker, Nginx, MongoDB, Bash, RESTful APIs, Linux, PostgreSQL, Webhooks, Elasticsearch

Cloud

AWS (CDK, EC2, ECS, EFS, IAM, Lambda, VPC, CloudMap, CloudWatch, Fargate), Digital Ocean Droplet, Heroku, Fly.io

EDUCATION

Saint Mary's University, Bachelor of Commerce (Bcom), Marketing Member of the Men's Varsity Hockey Team

2011 - 2016

NOTABLE ACHIEVEMENTS